David Perich

Profile

I'm a full stack software engineer in Melbourne, Victoria with experience in Node/JavaScript, Ruby/Rails, Docker, Kafka, React.js, and PostgreSQL. I am the co-creator of Venice ☑, an open-source framework for deploying and managing stream processing pipelines for small event-driven applications.

Professional Experience

01/2020 - present
Melbourne Australia

Venice, Co-Creator | Software Engineer

- Developed a containerised back-end infrastructure with Docker, consisting of: Apache Kafka, Zookeeper, Confluent Schema Registry, Kafka Connect, ksqlDB, Kafka Connect, PostgreSQL server, and Kafdrop
- Created a Node.js CLI to abstract and streamline the setup and management of event-stream processing pipeline.
- Used bash scripts to automate pipeline startup in containers, and to address race conditions between components in the pipeline
- Developed event producers in Python, Ruby and with the Twitter API as prototypes and motivating examples.
- Analysed event-stream processing eco-system to determine optimal components and configurations for small applications.
- Co-wrote engineering case study on the development of Venice https://veniceframework.github.io/

06/2018 - 12/2019Melbourne, Australia **Self Employed,** Full-Stack Web Software Developer

- Built a project management app similar to Trello with React/Redux and Rails
- Built a social news and discussion application with Rails, PostgreSQL, and JavaScript
- Built a personal task management app with Sinatra, PostgreSQL, and Handlebars.js

10/2016 - 12/2019Perth, Australia

Knowledge Society, Senior Consultant

- Led transformation projects for clients in government, education, aged-care sectors.
- Led data analytics capability, translating data into actionable insights for major projects.
- Other responsibilities: agile project management, workshop facilitation, client management.

Education

06/2018 – 11/2019 Remote	Launch School, Software Engineering & Full-stack Web Development
10/2015 - 07/2017 Perth, WA	University of Western Australia, Graduate Certificate Social Impact
08/2008 – 12/2010 Milwaukee, WI	Cardinal Stritch University, Bachelor International Business

Skills

Front Fnd

TIONE DIG
HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React/Redux,
jQuery, Bootstrap, Handlebars.js